Guide to the Papers of George L. Mosse (1918-1999), 1780-2001 AR 25137 / MF 671
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series I: Personal, 1897-2001; 4 linear feet
  - Subseries 1: George L. Mosse, 1927-2001; 3 linear feet
    After the death of Hilde L. Mosse in 1982 a foundation in her name was established in 1983. Since George Mosse was the President of the Foundation, materials related to the Hilde L. Mosse Center is located in this subseries.
    - A) General
      - 60th Birthday Invitation, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 70th Birthday Celebration - Poster, 1988 (Box OSL 41, Folder 1)
      - 80th Birthday - Greetings and Wishes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - 80th Birthday - Reminiscences, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - American Historical Association Seventieth Anniversary Meeting, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Auction of Hans-Lachmann-Mosse Library, 1927-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Auction of Jewelry, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Bootham School, 1934-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Caricature, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Citations Index - Arts and Humanities, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Citations Index - Social Science, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Commission of Enquiry into the Activities of Nazism in Argentina, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Donald Gray - Headmaster, Bootham School, York, 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Downing College (University of Cambridge), 1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Emigration - Exil - Exhibition Catalogue, 2000 (Box 60, Folder 1)
      - German Student Publications, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Grätz Family History, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hadassah Hospital, Jerusalem - Hilde L. Mosse Center, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Haverford College - Reunions, 1961, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Haverford College - School Reports, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Hebrew Union College - Commencement Exercises, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Life Insurance, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Medical Records, 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Obituary of Leonardo Olschki, 1961, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Permit to Enter Vatican Basilica for Easter Mass, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Personal Documents, 1933, 1939, 1958-1978, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Petition for Writ of Mandate, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Phonogram Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Porcelain Collection, 1966, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Projekt für Interdisziplinäre Faschismusforschung, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Research at Huntington Library - List of Readers and Their Projects, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Society Memberships, 1951, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Staadecker Familienstammbuch, 1905-1913 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Storia e Critica, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Swiss Banks and the Holocaust, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Università degli Studi di Camerino - Cena in Onore di George L. Mosse, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - University of Glasgow - List of Delegates and Honorary Graduands, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Violin Appraisal, 1983-1991 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Wisconsin Magazine of History, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Zwolf Merkwürdige Ausrufer von Berlin mit ihrem Geschrey, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - B) Acknowledgements, Awards, Degrees
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Boston - Fellow Certificate, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Boston - Fellow Certificate, 1985 (Box OSL41, Folder 2)
      - American Historical Association - Award for Scholarly Distinction, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Carthage College - Doctor of Literature Degree, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Cornell University - Andrew D. White Professor-at-Large Certificate, 1993 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      - GLB Alumni Council - Life Achievement Award, 1996 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Goethe-Institut - Goethe-Medaille Certificate, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Hadassah Acknowledgement of Gift - Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Harvard University - Master of Arts and Doctor of Philosophy Degrees, 1942, 1947 (Box OSL41, Folder 3)
      - Haverford College - Bachelor of Science, 1941 (Box OSL41, Folder 4)
      - Haverford College - Loyalty Recognition Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Hebrew Union College - Doctor of Humane Letters Degree, 1987 (Box OSL41, Folder 5)
      - Hebrew University - Doctor Honoris Causa Degree, 1999 (Box OSL41, Folder 6)
      - Melton Center for Jewish Studies, Ohio State University - Award, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Premio Prezzolini Award, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Universität-Gesamthochschule-Siegen - Doktor der Philosophie Honoris Causa, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - University of Wisconsin Foundation Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Wisconsin Library Association - Notable Wisconsin Author Award, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - C) Articles, Essays and Laudatia
      - Articles, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Articles, 1950-1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Articles, 1955-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Articles, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Articles, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Articles, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Articles, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Articles, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Articles, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Articles - Dutch, 1985-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Articles - French, 1987, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Articles - German, 1956-1958, 1978-1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Articles - Hebrew, 1962-1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Articles - Italian, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Articles - Italian, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Articles - Italian, 1986-1994 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Articles - Italian, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Articles - Norwegian, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Between Rationality and Irrationalism: George L. Mosse, the Holocaust and European Cultural History, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Cultural History and Symbols by John Ward - Review of Political Symbolism in Modern Europe: Essays in Honor of George L. Mosse, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Cultural History, Nationalism, and the Dignity of the Individual: the Work of George L. Mosse, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Curriculum Baedeker: From Art to Zoo, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Deutsche Juden jenseits des Judentums: Der Fall Gerhard George L. Mosse, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Deutsche-jüdische Emigrationshistoriker in den USA und der Nationalsozialismus, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Deutschlandbilder 1945-1965. Angloamerikanische Historiker und moderne deutsche Geschichte, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - " Du Baroque au nazisme: une histoire religieuse de la politique", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - "G.L.Mosse e il Problema delle Origini Culturali del Fascismo: Significato di una Svolta", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - German Politics and Society - Special Issues: George L. Mosse Symposium, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Laudatia, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Laudatia - Steve Ascheim: George Mosse at 80: A Critical Laudatio, 1999, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Laurea Honoris Causa a George L. Mosse, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Memorial Service - Speeches, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Nazisti ed ebrei nella Germania di George Mosse, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Necrologies, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Note agli Studi di George Mosse sul Nazismo, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Obituaries, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Partecipazione politica e integrazione comunitaria nella Germania nazista: un'analisi politologica di G.L.Mosse, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Razzismo e Omosessualità (Intervista a George L. Mosse), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Religione e politica nell'et… della secolarizzazione: riflessioni su di un recente volume di Emilio Gentile, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - D) Hilde L. Mosse Foundation
      - Contributions, 1982-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Contributions - Jewish Philanthropies, 1982, 1991, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Contributions - Madison Jewish Community Council, 1994-1998 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Contributions - Schomburg Center for Research in Black Culture, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Establishment, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Financial Statements, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Northside Center for Child Development, 1987-1998 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Computers - Photo Album, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - 50 Year Anniversary - Photo Album, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Golden Anniversary Gala, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Hilde Mosse Center - Poster, 1997 (Box OSL41, Folder 7)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Hilde Mosse Program - Photo Album, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Hilde Mosse Tutorial Center, 1992 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Hilde Mosse Tutorial Center - Letters, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Hilde Mosse Tutorial Center - Photo Album, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Homework Center - Photo Album, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Saturday, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Saturday Program - Celebration, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Northside Center for Child Development - Saturday Program - Literacy Group, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Portfolio Appraisal Reports, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Subseries 2: Family, 1897-1997; 0.5 linear foot
    The documents concerning George L. Mosse's family are comprised of general items relating to the Mosse and Lachmann families, as well as items pertaining to his mother Felicia, his sister Hilde, his grandfather Rudolf, and his father Hans. Personal documents comprise most of the material on Felicia, Hilde, and Hans. In addition, among the documents relating to Hilde Mosse are also articles, obituaries, and a memorial speech given by her brother. Material pertaining to Rudolf Mosse is in the form of articles and obituaries; there are no personal documents of his here. Articles concerning his publishing house and foundation as well as the Rudolf Mosse Educational Institute for Boys and Girls (Rudolf Mosse'sche Erziehungs-Anstalt für Knaben und Mädchen) will be found here.
    - A) Mosse Family
      - Articles on Mosse Family, undated, 1909?, 1918, 1925, 1944, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Lachmann Family Genealogy, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Mosse Family History, undated, 1909, 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - B) Felicia Lachmann-Mosse
      - Photos, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - C) Hilde Lachmann-Mosse
      - Articles by Hilde L. Mosse, 1959-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Ein Berliner Salon - A House Play, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Birth Certificate, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Estate, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Estate - Correspondence, 1982-1985, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Memorial Service Speech by George L. Mosse, 1982? (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Obituary, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Photos, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Portrait of Paul Ehrlich, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Tributes, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - D) Rudolf Mosse
      - Rudolf Mosse - Articles, undated, 1954, 1959, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Rudolf Mosse - Obituaries, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Rudolf Mosse Educational Institute - Annual Reports, 1897-1909 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Rudolf Mosse Foundation, 1966-1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Rudolf Mosse Publishing House - Print, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Mosse Zentrum - Veröffentlichungen zur Eröffnung, 1995 (Box OSL41, Folder 8)
    - E) Hans Lachmann-Mosse
      - Massenstraße - Photos, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Music Sheet Autographed by Franz Lehár, 1925 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Testament and Death Certificate, 1944, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Subseries 3: Calendars, 1957-1998; 0.5 linear foot
    Chronological.
    This subseries is comprised of daily planners which provide a view of George L. Mosse's daily life over a period of forty-one years. The calendars list appointments, meetings, and speaking engagements. Occasionally they also list tasks which need to be done.
    - Calendars, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Calendars, 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Calendars, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Calendars, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Calendars, 1970-1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Calendars, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Calendars, 1979-1981 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Calendars, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Calendars, 1985-1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Calendars, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Calendars, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Calendars, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Calendars, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Series II: Writings and Research, 1750-2001; 25.3 linear feet
  Divided into 5 subseries.
  Series II: Writings and Research holds the bulk of the scholarly material produced by George L. Mosse in this collection. The majority of documents found here are manuscripts and drafts of his writings, this series also contains research notes, index cards, and material he used in lectures and university courses.
  Having been a prolific writer, there is a large amount of material concerning Mosse's books which will be found here, including several different versions of his works. Research notes used for specific books will be found in Subseries 4 as well as in Subseries 5: Index Cards. Manuscripts and drafts of his books are located in Subseries 1. Reviews and reactions of his books by colleagues will be found in Subseries 2.
  In addition to books, George L. Mosse also wrote and published many articles and reviews covering various historical topics, often related to themes found in his published books.Articles written by him will be found in Subseries 1;reviews by others of these articles are located in Subseries 2.
  As a popular professor and well-known scholar, Mosse also spent a great deal of his time giving lectures. Lectures and other public talks given by him to groups or at professional conferences will be found in Subseries 3: Lectures, Conference Papers, and Courses. This subseries also includes material used by Mosse in some of his classes, especially those given at the University of Wisconsin at Madison.
  - Subseries 1: Writings, undated, 1945-2000; 8.25 linear feet
    by format and further alphabetically by title of the work
    This subseries contains manuscripts of George L. Mosse's writings, including his books, articles, reviews, research notes, and other projects in which Mosse participated.
    Manuscripts of his books contain drafts of his works. In addition, there are also notes on items George L. Mosse planned on inserting into his manuscripts, page proofs, and questions and queries from editors or readers concerning his manuscripts. The largest book represented in this section is Confronting History; materials concerning the autobiography include several drafts of the work, including three computer disks containing drafts. Material concerning The Image of Man includes not only drafts and inserts, but also reader's reports.
    The unpublished manuscripts and published versions of articles Mosse wrote for various journals, newspapers, and other publications can also be found in this subseries. Most articles focus on scholarly topics found throughout the collection, including fascism, nationalism, Jewish history, masculinity and sexuality, national socialism, and World War I. Articles published earlier in his career include those which focus on Puritanism, the Reformation, English history, and the teaching of history. In addition, correspondence concerning the articles may also be found here. Many of Mosse's works were translated into other languages; when possible these translations are listed under their English titles. Puritanism and Politics is a collection of previously written articles on Puritanism.
    Reviews written by George Mosse of other authors' books are also part of this subseries. Reviews are arranged chronologically by decade; those with more significant volume of material are further arranged alphabetically by author name. Reviews which were published in the New York Times Book Review are located separately in box 61.
    - A) Books
      - a)Confronting History
        - i) Contract
          - Contract, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - ii) Drafts
          - Chapter I, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
          - Chapter II, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
          - Chapter II, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
          - Chapter III, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 5)
          - Chapter IV, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
          - Chapters VI-VII, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
          - Chapters VIII-IX, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
          - Chapters X-XII, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
          - Computer Disks (3.5"), 1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
          - Introduction, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
          - Inserts, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
          - Photo List, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
          - Queries and Corrections, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        - iii) Edited Manuscript
          - Chapters I-IV, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
          - Chapters V-VII, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
          - Chapters VIII-X, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
          - Chapters XI-XIII, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
          - Title, Table of Contents, and Foreword, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
          - Editing Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
          - Editing Notes, undated, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
        - iv) Final Version
          - Introduction, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
          - Chapter I, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
          - Chapter II, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
          - Chapter III, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
          - Chapter IV, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 2)
          - Chapter V, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
          - Chapter VI, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
          - Chapter VII, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
          - Chapter VIII, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
          - Chapter IX, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - b)Confronting the Nation
        - Drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Drafts - Introduction, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Drafts - National Anthems: the Nation Militant, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - c)Crisis of German Ideology
        - Preface to the 1997 Edition - Draft (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - d)Fallen Soldiers
        - Foreword to Israeli Edition, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Picture Lists, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - e)Fascismo Verso Una Teoria Generale
        - Drafts, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - f)Fascist Revolution: Toward a General Theory of Fascism
        - Drafts, 1997-1998? (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - g)George Mosse: Ich Bleibe Emigrant: Gespräche mit George L. Mosse
        - English Translation, 1991? (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - h)Image of Man
        - Drafts, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - Inserts, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - Inserts - Not Used, undated, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - Page Proofs, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        - Reader's Reports and Marketing Questionnaires, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - Revisions, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - i)Source Readings - Western Civilization in Modern Times
        - Criticism and Revision Suggestions, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - B) Articles
      - 1915-18: la madre di tutti gli stermini, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Alltag im Dritten Reich, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - American Jewish Historical Quarterly Colloquium Article, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Amerikanische Geschichtsschreibung - Ein Überblick, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - Anatomy of Fascism, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Anti-League: 1844-1846, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - Art and Politics in Germany: A Comment, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - Articles in Corriere Cultura, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 31)
      - Assimilation of Machiavelli in English Thought: The Casuistry of William Perkins and William Ames, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Du Baroque au Nazismo - Une Histoire Religieuse de la Politique, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Beauty Without Sensuality, 1987-1991 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Beauty Without Sensuality- German Version Titled Schönheit ohne Sinnlichkeit, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Bildungsbürger Burn Their Own Books, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Bookburning and the Betrayal of German Intellectuals, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - Caesarism, Circuses, and Monuments, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - Can Nationalism be Saved? About Zionism, Rightful and Unjust Nationalism, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - Canto Della Patria, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - Central European Intellectuals in Palestine, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Challenge, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Change and Continuity in the Tudor Consitution, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Christian Statesman, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Corporate State and the Conservative Revolution in Weimar Germany, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Cultural Historian and Popular Culture, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Cultural Historian and Popular Literature, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Culture, Civilization and German Anti-Semitism, 1958, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Declino Della Morale, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Deputy's Dilemma, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Deutsch-Jüdische Bildungsbürgertum, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Deutscher Patriotismus und Jüdischer Nationalismus, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Deviant Identities: Jews and Others, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Dibattito sul Neo-Nazismo, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Ebrei e il Nazionalismo, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - End is Not Yet: a Personal Memoir of the German-Jewish Legacy of its American Context, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Erste Weltkrieg und die Brutalisierung der Politik, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - European Left and the War Experience: Germany and France, undated, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Fascism and the French Revolution, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Fascism and the Intellectuals, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Fascism as a Nationalist Movement: The Missing Link, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Fascist Aesthetics and Society: Some Considerations, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Fin-de-siècle. Challenge and Response, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Free Speech and the University, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - French Right and the Working Classes: Les Jaunes, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Freshman History: Reality or Metaphysics?, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Friendship and Nationhood: About the Promise and Failure of German Nationalism, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Friendship and Nationhood: About the Promise and Failure of German Nationalism - Spanish Version Titled Amistad y Conciencia Nacional: Promesa y Fracaso del Nacionalismo Aleman, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - George Lichtheim: Sketch for an Intellectual Portrait, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - German Jews and Liberalism in Retrospect, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
      - German Kultur of European Spirit, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - German Socialists and the Jewish Question in the Weimar Republic, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 32)